## JUAN CARLOS CONTRERAS OROPEZA

Frontend Developer & Engineering Professional

Front end developer with almost 2 years of experience using Vanilla JS, jQuery, Bootstrap, React, among other Frameworks; always applying the best practices, clean \$\infty\$+58 412 252 4311 code, and design patterns. Besides this interest, also I have qualities for leadership and management of teams and/or projects. Open to challenge, able to learn new disciplines quickly, good team-worker, a great worker among multicultural team environments, and independent worker if needed.

# **Professional Experience**

Swordvoice. Caracas, Venezuela Front end Developer & Mentor (Independent Professional)

May. 2020 – Currently (1yr + 10mth)

- Develop and implement functional components using ReactJS concepts.
- Support to clients in aspects of UX/UI design.
- Review the Web App's requirements in the user stories.
- Accompany and help people without previous knowledge in web development to reach an entry or junior level.

**Softnet & System Corp.** Caracas, Venezuela **Professional Services Manager** 

*Ago.* 2018 – *May.* 2020 (1yr + 10mth)

- Coordination of the areas of Presales, Projects, Functional Consulting, Software Development, and Infrastructure.
- Design of KPI, follow-up, and control of these to comply with the guidelines and objectives set in the company.

Softnet & System Corp. Caracas, Venezuela **Presales Coordinator** 

Jul. 2016 – Jul. 2018 (2yr + 1mth)

- Develop the conceptual, basic, and detailed engineering associated with the different solutions and products of the company.
- Advise clients, give presentations, and identify business opportunities.

#### **Courses & Certifications**

Sep. 2021	Front End Development Libraries (300 hours). freecodecamp.org/certification/contrer-ju/front-end-development-libraries
Feb. 2021	JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures (300 hours). freecodecamp.org/certification/contrer-ju/javascript-algorithms-and-data-structures
Oct. 2020	Responsive Web Design (300 hours). freecodecamp.org/certification/contrer-ju/responsive-web-design
Jun. 2013	Program in Project Management, Pro-PMI. (140 hours) Fundación Gerencia de Proyectos en Venezuela, Universidad Central de Venezuela.
Dec. 2009	English language. (9 levels of 48 hours each) Escuela de Idiomas Modernos, Universidad Central de Venezuela

Caracas, Venezuela

@ contrerju@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/contrerasjuanc/

codesandbox.io/u/contrer-ju

Ogithub.com/contrer-ju

🍩 contrer-ju.github.io

## **Education**

2001 - 2008

**Electrical Engineering**, **Option: Telecommunications** 

Universidad Central de Venezuela

1997 - 2000

Electrical Technician, **Option: Electronics** 

Instituto Universitario de Tecnología – Región Capital, "Dr. Federico Rivero Palacio"

## Skills

- HTML 5
- CSS3
- Responsive Web Design
- UX/UI Design
- Bootstrap: v4, v5
- JavaScript: ES6, ES7, ES8, ES9
- jQuery
- TypeScript
- React
- Git
- Cloud Computing: AWS-EC2
- Linux: Ubuntu, Debian
- Agile Development Methods: Scrum, Kanban.